smartsimpleuk.com 2018-11-26

# Privacy & Cookie Policies | SmartSimple

### Privacy Policy

## 1\. Introduction

**1.1** We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website and wiki visitors.

**1.2** This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of our website and wiki visitors; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.

**1.3** We use cookies on our website. Insofar as those cookies are not strictly necessary for the provision of our website, we will ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our website.

**1.4** Our website incorporates privacy controls which affect how we will process your personal data. By using the privacy controls, you can specify whether you would like to receive direct marketing communications and limit the publication of your information. You can access the privacy controls here.

**1.5** In this policy, "we", "us" and "our" refer to SmartSimple Software. For more information about us, see Section 8. The websites covered by this policy are the following: www.smartsimple.com; www.wiki.smartsimple.com; www.smartsimpleblog.com; 

## 2\. How we use your personal data

**2.1**

In this Section 2 we have set out:

  1. general information on how we collect information on this website
  2. the general categories of personal data that we may process;
  3. in the case of personal data that we did not obtain directly from you, the source and specific categories of that data;
  4. the purposes for which we may process personal data; and
  5. the legal bases of the processing.

**2.2** The personal information we collect can be divided into two main categories: **information you give us** , and **information we collect automatically**.

**Information You Give Us:**

We request to collect information from you when you are engaged in an of the following activities on our website:

  1. Job Application
  2. Demo Request
  3. General Inquiry
  4. Event Sign-Up
  5. Newsletter Sign-Up
  6. Webinar Sign-Up
  7. Content Downloads
  8. Partner Program Sign-Up
  9. Live Agent Chat
  10. GDPR Requests

You can choose whether or not to disclose your personal data while engaging in these activities. However, if you do not provide the information we have deemed mandatory, you will not be able to take full advantage of the website and its functions or content.

When you submit data on our website, you will be consenting to SmartSimple processing the categories of personal data that you have provided. The categories of personal data that we collect are as follows:

**Contact Data**

We may process your contact data ("contact data"). The contact data may include your first name, last name, email address, and phone number. The contact data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you, operating our website, providing our services, processing requests, record-keeping, and marketing and sales purposes. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

**Notification Data**

We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters, and/or downloading content, confirmation of event or webinar registration, changes to any current or future registrations, notifications if you change your communication preferences, removing you from our mailing list upon your request, and adding you or deleting you from our marketing database. ("notification data"). The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters, and/or content. The legal basis for this processing is consent.

**Correspondence Data**

We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us (" **correspondence data** "). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users.

**Inquiry Data**

We may process information contained in any inquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services (" **inquiry data** "). The inquiry data may be processed for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this processing is consent.

**GDPR Request Data**

We may process information contained in any GDPR Request you submit to us fulfilling your rights set out by the GDPR (“ **GDPR request data** ”). We will process this data for the purpose of fulfilling the request, communicating to you about the request, and sending you a validation once the request has been fulfilled. The legal basis for this processing is consent, OR if the processing is necessary to comply with our legal obligation as a controller.

**Job Application Data**

We may process data contained in any inquiry you make relating to job applications (“ **job application data** ”). This data may include address, city, country, province/state, postal/zip, work eligibility, employment status, level of education, work experience, desired annual salary, and anything you submit to us in your cover letter and/or resume. This data may be processed for human resources, hiring procedures, and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.

**Health Data**

We may process “ **health data** ”. We collect this data when you are signing to attend an in-person event with SmartSimple. This data may include food allergies, diet restrictions, and if you require special assistance.This data may be processed for the purposes of providing you appropriate accommodations at our event(s), should you require it. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR if processing is necessary in order to protect the vital interests of the data subject or of another natural person.

**Information We Collect Automatically:**

We request and/or request to collect information from you when you are engaged in an of the following activities on our website:

  1. Visiting our website

**Usage Data**

We may process data about your use of our website and services (" **usage data** "). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is Google Analytics. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

You can read more about cookies, and our use of them in our Cookie Policy (see below).

**More Information**

SmartSimple does not purchase marketing lists from third-parties.

We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.

In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 2, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

Please do not supply any other person's personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so.

## 3\. Providing your personal data to others

**3.1** We may disclose your personal data to any member of our group of companies (this means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries) insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes, and on the legal bases, set out in this policy. Information about our group of companies can be found in section 8.

**3.2** We use several third-party services to process the data we collect. We may process the following data categories: Contact Data, Usage Data, Notification Data, Inquiry Data, Correspondence Data, using our suppliers or subcontractors, namely Zoom, Unbounce, and Emma, insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes specified in section 2 for each respective category. The Personal Data will only be processed for the aforementioned purposes. Health Data and Job Application Data will never be processed by our processors. We have entered into a Data Processing Agreement with each of our processors to ensure that they comply with the General Data Protection Regulation, and protect your Personal Data in accordance with the highest standards.

**3.3** We use a third-party service to process some of the data we collect. We may process the following data category: Usage Data, using our supplier/subcontractor: Google Analytics, insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes specified in section 2 for. The Personal Data will **only** be processed for the aforementioned purpose. We have entered into a Data Processing Agreement with Google Analytics to ensure that they comply with the General Data Protection Regulation, and protect your Personal Data in accordance with the highest standards.

**3.4** In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 3, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.

## 4\. International transfers of your personal data

**4.1** In this Section 4, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

**4.2** SmartSimple has offices in Canada, the United States, and Ireland. The European Commission has made an "adequacy decision" with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. According to the European Commission, Canada offers adequate protections for the transfer of data. Data transferred to Canada will be covered by the adequacy decision. Transfers to the United States will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission.

**4.3** The hosting facilities for our website are situated in Canada. The European Commission has made an "adequacy decision" with respect to the data protection laws of each of Canada. Transfers to Canada will be protected by the adequacy decision.

**4.4** SmartSimple uses the following subcontractors to assist some data processing: Zoom Video Communications Inc., Google Analytics, Emma, and Unbounce Marketing Solutions Inc.. These subcontractors are situated in the United States. The European Commission has made an "adequacy decision" with respect to the data protection laws of the United States. Transfers to the United States will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or approved by the European Commission OR the EU-U.S. Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

**4.5** You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website or services may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal data by others.

## 5\. Retaining and deleting personal data

**5.1** This Section 5 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.

**5.2** Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.

**5.3** We will retain your personal data as follows:

_Usage Data_ will be retained for a maximum period of _26 months_ following the _date of collection_.

_Contact Data_ will be retained for a maximum period of _5 years_ following the _date of collection_.

_Notification Data_ will be retained for a maximum period of _5 years_ following the _date of collection_.

_Correspondence Data_ will be retained for a maximum period of _5 years_ following the _date of collection_.

_Inquiry Data_ will be retained for a maximum period of _5 years_ following the _date of collection_.

_GDPR Request_ Data will be retained for a maximum period of _one (1) day_ after the request has been fulfilled.

_Job Application Data_ will be retained for a minimum period of the _job application process following the application date_ , and for a maximum period of _5 years_ following application rejection date. If the job applicant is successful, the data will be subject to the SmartSimple’s Human Resources Policy.

_Health Data_ will be retained for a minimum period of _(1) day_ post event date, and for a maximum period of _6 months_ following the _date of collection_.

**5.4** Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 5, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

## 6\. Amendment

**6.1** We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.

**6.2** You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.

**6.3** We may notify you of changes to this policy by email or through a notification on this website.

## 7\. Your rights

**7.1** In this Section 7, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

**7.2** Your principal rights under data protection law are:

  1. the right to access;
  2. the right to rectification;
  3. the right to erasure;
  4. the right to restrict processing;
  5. the right to object to processing;
  6. the right to data portability;
  7. the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and
  8. the right to withdraw consent

**7.3 The Right of Access.** You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee.

**7.4 The Right to Rectification.** You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.

**7.5 The Right to Erasure.** In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

**7.6 The Right to Restriction of Processing.** In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.

**7.7 The Right to Object to Processing.** You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

**7.8 The Right to Object to Processing for Marketing Purposes.** You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

**7.9 The Right to Complain to a Supervisory Authority.** If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

**7.10 The Right to Withdraw Consent.** To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.

**7.11 The Right to Data Portability.** To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:

  1. consent; or
  2. that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

**7.12 How to Exercise Your Rights.** You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us OR by clicking here.

## 8\. Our details

**8.1** This website is owned and operated by _SmartSimple Software Inc._

**8.2** We are registered in:

  1. Canada as _SmartSimple Software Inc._ , A Federally Incorporated Corporation located at 111 Peter St. Suite 405, Toronto, Ontario, M5V 2H1;
  2. Ireland as _SmartSimple Software Ireland Limited_ located at 9 Grattan Business Park, Clonshaugh, Dublin 17, D17 PW27;
  3. United States as _SmartSimple Software Ltd._ , A Delaware Corporation located at 33 West 19th Street, 4th Floor New York, NY, United States, 10011

**8.3** Our principal place of business is at _111 Peter Street, Suite 405 Toronto, Ontario, Canada M5V 2H1_

**8.4** You can contact us:

  1. by post, to 111 Peter Street, Suite 405 Toronto, Ontario, Canada M5V 2H1;
  2. using our website contact form;
  3. by telephone, on 416.591.1668;
  4. by email, using gdpr@smartsimple.com

## 9\. Data protection officer

**9.1** Our data protection officer’s contact details are:

Michael Tan  
416.591.1668 Ext. 145
